字幕碓矗浩嬗鲭影字幕M
字幕特效：101eagle
褐疲101eagle
上UP：101eagle
Ruth?
露z?
Where's my wife?
我妻子在哪
Mr. Guttman!You can't be sneaking up on me like that!
古特曼先生 你可不能@油低翟诒翅我一跳
Where is my wife?Where is Ruth?
我太太呢 露z在哪Y
I'm sorry, Mr. Guttman,
很抱歉 古特曼先生
your wife passed away about a week ago.
你太太大s一周前^世了
Ah.
噢
I'm sorry. Who are you?
抱歉 你是?
My name's Paula.
我叫保拉
I was Mrs. Guttman's nursing aide.
曾是古特曼太太的o理
Your family asked me to stay on for another week or two.
你家我再多待一芍
Let's get some breakfast.
去吃c早餐吧
You'll be feeling better after breakfast.
吃完早餐你感X好些的
Where are your shoes?
你的鞋在哪
Hold on, let me get you some slippers.Tell you what.
等等 我去o你拿拖鞋
Trade your hat for some slippers, okay?
用你的帽子去Qp拖鞋 可以
All right. Now come in.
好了 M戆
Good morning, Zev.  Good morning.
- 早安 煞 - 早安
I hope you're not too hungry.Breakfast is crummy as usual.
但你]有很I 早餐和往常一由俚每z
That's okay.I'm not too hungry.
]PS 我不是很I
That's Cele. She was friends with your wife.
她是塞R 你太太以前的朋友
I know who she is.I know who she is.
我知道她是l 我知道
Could you give us a minute, please?
能o我私聊的rg
Oh, no problem...
噢 ]}
Max.
他是R克斯
You don't have to tell me everyone's name.
你]必要告V我所有人的名字
Tonight is the last night sitting shiva for Ruth, yes?
今晚是槁督z服实淖钺嵋煌
Do you remember what you said you would do
你不得你f^露z死後
when Ruth died?
你要做什N
No.
不得了
It's okay. It's okay.
]事 ]事
I...
我
wrote everything down
下了所有事
so you...
所以你
could remember.
起淼
Come on, Mr. Rosenbaum.
跟我 谏U姆先生
Darling.
H鄣
Do you know when this picture was taken?
你知道@照片什Nr候照的
It's from their wedding day.
他Y婚的r候照的
1946.
1946年
Did you meet nanny in Germany?
你是在德遇奶奶的
Uh, no, no.
噢 不 不是
I met her in America.I met her...
我在美遇她的
Coney...
在康尼
Coney Island.  Yeah.
- 在康尼u -
Why don't you show this to your brother, eh?
嘿 槭颤N不拿o你哥哥看看呢
Adam, look at this!
快看@
Here. Put this away in your pocket.
o 把@放口袋Y
Now,
F在
stand up.
站起
Tell everyone you're tired,
告V所有人你累了
and go read it alone.
然後自一人看完
Alone.
自一人
You're tired.
你累了
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. Good.
就@ 好的
Forgive me, I...
原我 我
I'm a little tired,I think I should go to bed.
我有c累 我想我去睡X了
Yeah. Okay, Dad.
好的 爸爸
It's been a long week.
真是漫L的一周
Yeah.
是啊
Penn Station, right?  Yeah.
- 佩恩站  - 是的
Last call!
最後通知
49 Lake Shore Limited!
49湖I列要l了
Last call!
最後通知
Last call,49 Lake Shore Limited!
最後通知 要_了
Is that your mother?
那是你
Yeah.
是的
She's not coming with you?
她不和你一起
No. I'm going to see my dad.
不 我去找我爸爸
Oh.
噢
So, you're traveling all alone?
所以你是一人咯
I'm not alone.My brothers are right over there.
不是一人 我的兄弟在那呢
Oh?
噢?
Oh, I see.
噢 我看了
Are you going to Cleveland too?
你也是去克利夫m
Yeah.
是的
Why don't you fly?It's faster.
槭颤N不坐wC呢 那痈快
I don't know.
我也不知道
That's not a good reason.
@可不是好理由
You're a real whipper snapper, aren't you?
你@不知天高地厚的小孩
Why don't you fly to Cleveland?
那你槭颤N不坐wC去克利夫m呢
Three plane tickets is too expensive.
三wC票太F了
That's what my mom and dad said.
那是我爸f的
Well, that is a good reason.
好吧 @是好理由
I don't fly because my friend told me to take the train
我不坐wC是因槲遗笥言谒o我的信Y
in the letter he wrote to me.
告V我要坐火
I guess that's a good reason, too.
我想@也是好理由
My name is Tyler.
我叫泰勒
Nice to meet you, Tyler.
很高dJR你 泰勒
My name's Zev.
我叫煞
That's a strange name.
真是奇怪的名字
In Hebrew, it means "Wolf."
在希伯碚ZY 它的意思是"狼"
Cool!
真酷
I have planned everything for you.
我槟阌了所有事
You must follow these steps precisely.
你必精实绦羞@些步E
Cross them off as you accomplish each task.
每做完一就掉一
We've notified the police and they've issued
我已通知^警方 他向社^l出了
a silver alert as well as a reverse 911
y色警K臃911系y
to the community, our...our staff is doing all that we can.
我...我@竭M全力
It's upsetting.  I just can't believe
- _y以接受... - 我只是不敢相信
this is happening.
l生的@一切
I can't tell you how sorry we all are.
我感到f分的抱歉
We do our best to keep an eye on everybody,
我密切留意每人
but... I'm sure you can understand.
但...我相信你能理解的
Is there anything we can do to help?
我能偷绞颤N
Besides paying you to lose people?
除了付X你看G人有e的
Does your father have a credit card?
你父H有信用卡
You can tell them to call you if he uses it.
他一旦使用你可以y行M你
Listen.
著
Your mother's nursing aid told me that
你母H的o工告V我
your dad's been very confused lately.
你父H最近特e糊T
Yeah, yeah.That's because he has dementia.
是的 他患有V呆
And that's why my mother brought them here in the first place.
而@也是起初我母H把父H一起У竭@淼脑因
I understand that. However,
我明白 但是
it's very common after the death of a spouse
通常在配偶死亡後
for more signs of neurocognitive disorders to emerge.
出F更多J知障K
Have you noticed that your father's been having mood swings?
你有]有注意到你父H的情w波
And he rarely plays the piano anymore?
而且他缀醪辉琴了
I've noticed a few things, Charles.
我察X到了一些 查斯
I guess we were...
我想那r我
so busy with your mom that I just dismissed them.
在你母H的事情上太操诹艘灾领段]有理@些
Let me reassure you,we'll have him back here before you know it.
安心吧 我他在你知郧捌桨不淼
In these situations,
在@些情r下
people never wander too far.
人不走太h
Ruth?
露z?
Adam?
?
Where is your grandmother?
你奶奶在哪
Adam?
?
Where is your grandmother?
你奶奶呢
Were you talking to me, Zev?
你在跟我f 煞
I asked you where your grandmother is.
我你奶奶在哪
One is in New York.One is in Ohio.
一在~s州 一在俄亥俄州
Where is your sister?
你妹妹呢
I don't have a sister.
我]有妹妹
Stop playing with that thing.
e玩那玩意毫
Answer me.
回答我
Are... are you okay, Zev?
你...好 煞
Where are we?
我在哪
We're on a train.
在火上
To where?
去哪
Cleveland.
克利夫m
Cleveland?
克利夫m?
You're going to see a friend.
你要去一朋友
What friend?
什N朋友
The one who wrote you the letter in your pocket.
o你了你口袋Y那封信的朋友
Can I have my PSP back?
能把我的[Co我了
Ruth is dead.
露z死了
Zev,
煞
I'm going to sit with my brothers for a little bit.
我要去和我兄弟坐一
Excuse me.  Yeah?
- 你好 - 嗯?
Hi. Uh...My son there said that you were sitting
嗨 我... 我鹤釉诨疖上r你和他挨著
next to him on the train and that you seemed a little confused.
而你看起碛行┖T了
Oh, yes, that.
噢 是的
I'm sorry about that.  Oh, no, no, no.
- 我Υ烁械胶鼙歉 - 噢 不不
There's no need to apologize. We...
你不需要道歉 我...
just want to make sure you're okay.  Oh, yes, I'm okay.
- 只是想_J你]事 - 噢我]事的
Thank you. I'm okay.
xx你 我很好
Um... You need help getting somewhere?
~...你要去哪需要兔
No, no.Someone will be meeting me here.
不用 有人斫游业
My friend said that he had a...
我朋友f他e一
sign with my name on it.
有我姓名的牌子
Okay. Well, we'll help you find him.
好的 我湍阏
The cars are just down here.
@些到
Is your last name Guttman?
你是姓古特曼
Yeah.
是的
Looks like you're riding in style.
你坐的看起砗r髦
Bye, Zev.
再 煞
Goodbye. Goodbye.
再 再
Let's go, boys.
走吧 孩子
Mr. Guttman?  Yeah.
- 古特曼先生? - 是的
Good.
好的
Good evening.  Evening.
- 下午好 - 下午好
How can I help you?
我怎偷侥隳
My friend recommended your shop to me.
我朋友向我推]了你的店
Well, tell your friend we appreciate the recommendation.
好的 D告你的朋友我很感x他的推]
What are you looking to pick up?  Oh...
- 你想要拿哪N呢 - 噢...
Something small.
小一c的
Sure thing. Okay.
然有
Can I see your driver's license?  Yeah.
- 能o我看看你的{C - 好的
Yeah...
@...
Okay.
好的
Beachwood. Nice town.
比奇伍德 很棒的小
Yes. But, um...
是的 但...
We've moved.
我搬走了
We live closer to my son.
我搬去x我鹤痈近的住了
What are you doing with my license?
你拿我的{C质颤N
I'm entering your information into the FBI background check database.
我在把你的信息入FBI的背景{查
Oh.
噢
What do they look for?
他在{查什N
A bunch of stuff.Whether you're a convicted felon,
一大堆Y料 看你是否橐驯欢ㄗ锏闹匦谭
if you've been involved in a crime of violence,
涉嫌暴力犯罪
dishonorably discharged from the army,
被徒涿饴
mentally competent.If you've got more than one DUI offense
是否智力健全 或者是否^去五年
in the last five years,if you're a fugitive,
不止一次酒{ 是否是逃犯
or currently charged with a felony.  Fugitive?
- 或者最近被指控重罪 - 逃犯?
Yeah, like, if you're running from the law.
是的 比如你在逃法律的制裁
Do I look like I can run?
你X得我看起硖拥
Uh, okay. Let me show you some of our smaller handguns.
好吧 o你看些小一c的手
We got everything.SIG Sauers, 1911s, Glocks,
我有M有 西格B M1911 格洛克（均槭型）
single action, double action.
p
Sir, do you know much about guns?  Um...
- 先生 你懂 - ~...
No. Why?     It's all right.
- 不懂 怎N了 - 那]PS
We get all types in here.
我@什N型的都有
Uh, okay. Beginners...
好吧 新手的...
usually go with a .22.
通常是用c22口降
It's light. Easy to use.Very little recoil.
它很p 易上手 後坐力很小
I think that's what my friend suggested.
我X得@就是我朋友建h的
Okay. In my opinion,
好吧 依我砜
you might as well get yourself a BB gun if you get a .22.
你Ic22就相於碛辛艘话
Look, I'm not trying to give you the hard sell, but $500 more,
嘿 我不是在行推N 但多花500K
you can get yourself a gun with real stopping power.
你能碛幸话颜嬲有制幽芰Φ
Now this is a 9mm Glock 17.
@是格洛克17 9mm手
Glock? It is German, no?
格洛克? @是德
You're in the right neighborhood.Manufactured in Austria.
接近正_答案了 它a自W地利
That's the most popular law enforcement pistol in the world. Okay?
@是世界上最流行的谭ㄊ 不e吧
It's got very little recoil so probably won't hurt your hand
它的後坐力非常小 所以不到手
but it'll definitely hurt the intruder.
但它肯定到入侵者
Is it easy to use?
@好用
I hope!
但
Yeah, it's simple.
是的 它很易
Yeah, but...
好吧 但是...
Would you mind, could you...
不知你介不介意 可不可以
write down the instructions for me?
臀使用f明
Uh, sure. I mean,I can show you how to use it.
然可以 我的意思是 我可以示o你看怎N使用
No, that would be good.But please, write it down for me.
不了 那是很好 但拜了 臀下戆
Sometimes I forget things.
我有r候健忘
Yeah, we all do, right?That's no problem.
客至上 @]}
Okay, you're good to go.
好的 一切都妥了
I'll grab a pen, and um...
我去拿支P 然後
write it all down for you.
湍下使用f明
Mr. Guttman?    Guttman. Yeah...
- 古特曼先生 -  古特曼
How did you know?
你怎N知道
Your friend called earlier and said you'd be arriving soon.
你朋友早些r候打^f你快到了
Your room's all ready for you.
房g已槟浜昧
We have you in...
房g是
125. Just down the hall.
125 就著走廊走
How much do I owe?  It's all taken care of,
- 我付多少X - 已付^了
including incidentals.
包括附加M
Oh, and I booked your taxi for the morning,like your friend asked.
α 你朋友的要求 我槟阌了明天早上的出租
Thank you.
xx你
Hello?  Hello.
- 喂? - 喂
Zev?    Yeah.
- 煞 - 是我
It's Max.
我是R克斯
I gave the hotel some instructions.
我指示了酒店一些事
Are you okay?  Yes, yes, I'm okay, Max.
- 你好 - 是的我好 R克斯
And you got the gun?
你拿到了
Yeah, yeah.
嗯 拿到了
Good. Good.
很好 很好
You know what to do.
你知道做什N的
Just take care of yourself, yeah?
照好自己 知道
You have a good night, Max.
晚安好 R克斯
Good night, Zev.
晚安 煞
Ruth?
露z?
Turn on the lights, please.
你把舸蜷_好
It's dark in here. I can't...
太黑了 我看不...
I can't see.
看不清楚
Hello.        Hi.
- 你好 - 嗨
Is Rudy Kurlander home?
迪・焯m德在家
Yeah. He is downstairs.
在家 他在窍
Are you...
你是...
Rudy Kurlander?
迪・焯m德?
Yes.
是
I'm Rudy Kurlander.
我是迪・焯m德
Who are you?
你是?
Can you, uh...
你可以...呃...
turn off the television?
把P掉
Do I know you?
我JR你
Now, please...
F在 你...
stand by the window.
站到窗襞赃
Who are you?
你是l
Stand by the window.
站到窗襞赃
I am not going to do anything until you tell me
如果你不告V我你是l有你磉@旱脑因
who you are and why you're here.
我什N都不做
Let us not argue.
咱是e了
Just stand by the window.
站到窗去
Now what?
F在又要做什N
I need to see light on your face.
得亮堂些我才能看清你的
Turn your head.        Who are you?
- 把^D^去 - 你是l
Don't yell.
e吼
Please, don't yell.
拜 不要吼
Do as I say. Turn your head.
按我f的做 抬起^
Are you German?
你是德人
Yeah.
是的
You are also German?        Ja.
- 你也是德人? (德Z) - 是
How old are you?
你多少q了
88 Eighty-eight.
Were you in the German army?
你曾在德服役
What did you do?
你在Y做什N
It is in the past.        English. Please, English.
- 那都^去了 - 英Z f英Z
I do not like to speak German.        It's seventy years ago.
- 我不喜gf德Z - 那都是70年前了
I was very young-
我那r太年p
Answer the question.
回答我的}
Are you a Jew?
你是q太人?
Yeah.
]e
Were you at Auschwitz?        No!
- 你r在W斯S辛集中I - 我不在
We are too old for lies.
我都@q盗 有必要撒e
I didn't know about Auschwitz
在Y束前
until after the war.
我都不知道W斯S辛集中I的事
I was in North Africa.
我r在北非
With General Rommel.
和隆美元一起
You have proof?        Yes.
- 你有C - 有
Over there.
就在那
When I became a US citizen, the immigration officer asked me
我成槊公民的r候 移民局的官T我
if I had ever associated
是否曾和{粹政府
with the Nazi government of Germany
有P
or worked at a concentration camp.
或者是否曾在集中I工作
I told the officer what I'll tell you.
我的回答f
Yes, I served for my country. I was a soldier.
是的 我效忠於我的家 我是一名人
I was a proud German and that's what the men did.
我樽约荷榈人而自豪 所有人都樽约旱家而自豪
I'm still proud of my service.
我仍然槲家作出的I感到自豪
That's Rommel.
@是隆美元
As far as the Jews...
至於q太人
I didn't care about the Jews. I thought Hitler was right.
我K不P心q太人 我J橄Ｌ乩帐Φ
They caused many problems for the country.
q太人o我家砹颂多麻
I thought we were deporting them or putting them in work camps...
我J槲是在逐他 或是把他安置在IY...
Not what they did.
而不是像他所做的那
It was shameful,
那太可u了
but that was not me.
但我]有做那些事
Hello?        Is this Max?
- 喂? - 是R克斯
Yes.
是我
This is Zev.
我是煞
Uh... It was...
呃... 不是...
not him.
不是他
Are you sure?        Yeah, I'm sure.
- 你_定 - 我_定
Then you must go on.
那你必要^m
You must do
必履行
what you said you would.
你曾承Z^的
There have been rumors for years
近些年硪恢庇髀
that a number of Auschwitz SS officers
一些W斯S辛集中IY的hl官
stole the identities of executed prisoners
在接近尾的r候
near the end of the war.
冒名替了被死的q太人的身份
Shortly after my stroke,
在我中L後不久
evidence was found that an Auschwitz Blockfuhrer
有C表明 一名W斯S辛集中I官
emigrated from Germany in the 1940s
於19世o40年代牡移民
and was most likely living under the name
K且最可能用假名迪・焯m德
Rudy Kurlander.
^m生活
The Simon Wiesenthal Center
西蒙・S森塔中心(西蒙・S森塔中心是一Hq太人嘟M @M是榱思o念{粹在二次世界大鹬斜⒌莫q太人而成立的)
has found four Rudy Kurlanders
找到了四名在那r期移民至此的
who emigrated during that period.
迪・焯m德
However, there is not enough proof
然而 ]有足虻淖C
to arrest any of them.
逮捕他其中任何一人
His real name is Otto Wallisch.
他的真名是W托・瓦利施
You must find him.
你必要找到他
I'm looking for my father. He's almost 90 years old.
我正在ふ椅腋赣H 他已⒔90q了
His name is Zev.
他的名字叫煞
I'm looking for my father.
我在ふ椅业母赣H
He's 90 years old.
他90q了
He went wandering a few days ago.
他滋烨巴獬鲩f逛
His name is Zev Guttman.
他的名字是煞颉す盘芈
I don't know if he has any identification on him,
我不知道他是否S身yЯ丝梢宰C明身份的C件
or... I don't even know if he remembers his name.
我甚至不_定他是否得自己的姓名
I've been wondering if anybody has been brought into the hospital.
我想知道有]有人被送Mt院
Do you not think I've already called the police?
你X得我]缶
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士先生
we're approaching the Canadian border,
我快到加拿大境了
at which point, we're all gonna have to get off the bus for inspection.
到r候大家都需要下接受z查
If you can have your passports and any travel documents ready,
如果您能提前浜媚的o照或其他旅行C件
it'll make the process a lot faster. Thank you.
⒐省不少rg xx合作
Declaration card?
出示申
Purpose of your trip?
您此行的目的是?
To see a friend.
拜L一位朋友
What's your friend's name?
您朋友的姓名是?
Rudy Kurlander.       Where does he live?
- 迪・焯m德 - 他住哪
Foyer Des... Foyer...
福伊・德斯...福伊...
Can I see that?        Yeah, of course.
- 我能看看 - 然可以
Foyer Des Pionniers Nursing Home?        Yeah.
- 福伊・德斯先者B老院? - 是的
And you'll be staying at the Queen's Motel in Hearst, Ontario?
您⑷胱“泊舐允『账固氐幕屎笃旅^?
That's right.
]e
How long will you be in Canada?
您⒃诩幽么笸Ａ舳嗑
Two nights. Maybe.
大概赏戆
Passport?
o照
Sir, your passport's expired.
先生 您的o照^期了
It is?        Yeah.
- ^期了? -
Do you have a driver's license?
您有{照
Oh, of course.
噢 然有
Hang on a second.
稍等
Alright, you're good to go.
好了 您可以走了
But, sir, renew your passport.
不^您⒆o照延期
I didn't think it was necessary at my age.
我都@q盗 用不著了
Have fun with your friend.
祝您c朋友相聚愉快
Thank you.
xx
Excuse me.
打_一下
How can I help you, sir?
需要什N椭 先生
Rudy Kurlander. Which room is he in?
迪・焯m德在哪房g
Kurlander?
焯m德?
Yes, Kurlander. He's in room 238.
焯m德 他在238房
Just go down this hallway and take the elevators.
沿著@l走廊走 坐梯
When you exit the elevator, make a left, then you take a right.
出梯後 左D 再右D
238 will be on your left.
238房就在你的左手
Did you get that?
明白了
Why don't I just show you where your friend's room is?
我直接您去您朋友的房g吧
Thank you.
xx
Are you Rudy Kurlander?
你是迪・焯m德
Rudy Kurlander?
迪・焯m德?
Here.
我是
Are you Rudy Kurlander?        Yeah.
- 你是迪・焯m德? - 是的
Are you German?
你是德人
Yes.
是的
Were you at Auschwitz?
你以前在W斯S辛集中I
Yes.
是的
I was at Auschwitz.
我去^W斯S辛集中I
My whole family was
我全家人都在
murdered
W斯S辛集中I
at Auschwitz.
被⒘
I'm so sorry.
我感到很抱歉
You're... you're sorry?
你很...很抱歉?
Yeah.
]e
What you did is something you cannot apologize for.
你的所作所椴皇堑歉就足虻
I swore I would kill the man responsible
我l^誓我⑺
for the death of my family.
⒑ξ胰家性命的那人
You're Jewish?
你是q太人?
Homosexual.
我是同性
It is I who am sorry.
是我道歉才
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry!
Σ黄 真的很抱歉
Moszkowski.
莫什科夫斯基
You know Moszkowski?
你知道莫什科夫斯基?
My old piano teacher used to say
我以前的琴老曾f
that the three greatest composers
三位最ゴ蟮淖髑家分e是
were Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer
T德松 梅耶
and Moszkowski.
以及莫什科夫斯基
Do you still play?        Oh...
- 你F在 - 噢...
No.
不
No, I don't know, I'm not sure!
不 我不知道 我不_定
Well...
那N...
Why don't you give it a try?
槭颤N不呢
Oh... Well...
噢... 好吧...
Mendelssohn.
T德松
Maybe.
大概吧
Hello, sir. Welcome to Boise.
你好 先生 g迎淼讲┮廖
Do you have a reservation?
您A定^了
I have a note that you need a taxi pickup at 8:00 am.
我@有您早上8c需要出租服
So, we have our complimentary breakfast which starts at 6:00 a.m.
我㈧6c起供免M早餐
And if you just head through the lobby to your left...
如果您街贝┻^左手的大d...
Here, let me help you, okay?
我椭您 好
There is one thing. I forgot to pack more clothes.
有件事 我忘了б路了
Extra clothes.        Oh!
- Q洗的衣服 - 噢
We can definitely help you out with that.
@完全不是}
So, there's a downtown shuttle that leaves every hour on the hour
每整c都有一趟公共汽奈@Yl往市中心
and it's going to drop you right off at the mall on North Milwaukee street.
@趟⒛送到北密沃基路的商
You should be able to get everything you need there...
您可以在那I到您需要的所有|西
Sir, would you like me to do that?
先生 你需要我湍A
Sir, are you okay?
先生 您好
Would you like to head up to your room now? Okay.
您F在想去您的房g了 好勒
Can I help you find anything?        Oh, yes.
- 您需要我湍阏沂颤N - 噢 是的
I want to buy a new shirt.
我想I一件新r衫
We have a great deal on short-sleeve button downs.
我有很多短袖系扣r衫
Yeah?        Can I show you?
- 是 - 您要看看
Thank you.        Yeah.
- 隈{ - 不客
You can always find the best deals at the end of the season.
季末的r候最划算了
Oh, right.
好的
Excuse me, sir. You set off the alarm.
抱歉 先生 您|了警
I'm gonna have to check your bag.
我得z查一下您的包
Oh. Do I look like a thief?
噢 我看起硐\
Oh, it doesn't matter, sir, you set off the alarm.
噢 跟@]PS 先生 您|了警
I've got to check your bag no matter what, so...
不管怎游叶嫉z查一下您的包
There's the receipt.
@是收
Oh, there's your problem right there.
噢 }在@
They left the security tag on.
他忘把安全嘶`取下了
I'll have to check your other bag too, sir.
我得z查一下您另外一包 先生
Is that a Glock?
@是一把格洛克
Yeah.
是啊
Reminds me of my first gun.
我想起了我第一把
You have a good day, sir.
祝您今天^得愉快 先生
There you go. Thanks very much.        Thank you. Thank you...
- o您 非常感x - xx xx
Would you like a refill?
您要m杯
Yes. Thank you.        You're very welcome.
- 好的 xx - 不客
Could you tell me how far is Bruneau is from here?
你能告V我倪@旱讲剪Z有多h
I've never actually been to Bruneau, but it's in Owyhee County,
我]去^布Z 不^那是在W严？
so, I'd say that should probably take you about 30, 40 minutes or so.
所以 我X得大概是三四十分的路程吧
Oh.        I heard it's beautiful country down there.
- 噢 - 我f那旱泥l下很漂亮
I never get to go but my friends...
我]去^但是我朋友...
Oh!        Ah.
- 噢 - 啊
Oh, I'm so sorry!
噢 我很抱歉
I got coffee on your letter.        Oh, God.
- 我把咖啡撒到你的信上了 - 噢 天啊
No, you're ruining my letter!
住手 你把我的信Я
No, no, no!        I'm sorry.
- 不要 不要 不要 - 我很抱歉
This letter is very important! Stop! Stop! Stop!
@封信很重要 住手 住手 住手
"Besides me,
除了我
"you are the only person
你是唯一一
"who can still recognize
仍然能J出
"the face of the man
那人L相的人
"who murdered our families."
他⒑α宋的家人
Nobody's home?        No.
- ]人在家 - ]有
You want me to take you somewhere else?
您想我把您送到其他地方
No, no, no. I will wait.        Here.
- 不不不 我再等等 - o您
Give me a call whenever you want me to come back and get you.
您什Nr候需要我回斫幽就o我打
What do I owe you?
我付你多少X
Oh, you already paid me, remember?
噢 您已付^X了 得
Just call me if you need a ride later.
如果你需要乘o我打就行
Morning.
早安
Morning to you too, sweetie.
你也早安 小可
Yeah...
]e...
Dinner time, Mr. Rosenbaum.
吃晚了 谏U姆先生
Bring me back some food, yeah?
o我c吃的 可以
Are you sure? You haven't been outside the apartment all day.
您_定 您已在房gY待了一整天了
Yes.        Okay.
- 我_定 - 好吧
Can I help you with something?
我能湍什N
I'm looking for Rudy Kurlander.
我碚音迪・焯m德
Well, you came to the right place but, uh...
呃 您Φ胤搅 但是...
My old man passed away about three months ago.
我的爸爸3月前去世了
Oh, I didn't know this. I am so sorry.
噢 我不知道@ 我很z憾
How long have you been waiting here?
您在@旱攘硕嗑昧
All day.
一整天
You want a drink?
您要喝c什N
A drink would be nice.
那好O了
Come on in.
M戆
I could use another drink myself.
我自己也睃c
Thank you.        Beer or a water?
- xx你 - 要啤酒是水
Just water, please.
水就可以了 xx你
Oh, Eva. Good girl. Good girl.
哦 伊娃 乖 e叫了
Listen, I am a little scared of dogs.
著 我有c怕狗
Eva's all bark and no bite.Come on in.
伊娃不咬人的 M戆
But I'm sure that's true but I'm... I'm quite scared.
我相信你 但我是U害怕的
Oh, I'll put her away for you. Okay.
哦 我把它ё ]}的
Here we go. Good girl.
我走 好拥
Quiet, girl. Eva!
e叫了 伊娃
Eva, shush, quiet.
伊娃 u 安o
Girl, quiet. Calm down, Eva. Shush.
安o e叫了 伊娃 u
Eva, shush. Shush.
伊娃 u u
Eva, calm down now. Calm down.
伊娃 安o下 安o
Quiet!
e叫了
That's my, um, kid's graduation.
那是我鹤拥漠I照
Dad always loved that photo.
我父H一直很喜g那照片
- I'm gonna get... grab your water for you. - Yeah.
- 我去...拿水o你 - 好的
When was that taken? Your father looks so young.
@照片什Nr候拍的  你父H看起砗苣贻p
That was, uh, in 1997.
那是 ~ 1997拍的
- Oh. - Yeah. Dad aged well, didn't he?
- 哦 - Π 老益 不是
1997 1997.
He always said that he was one of the Kurlanders with good genes.
他一直f他是焯m德家族基因最好的
Here you go.
o你
Oh, you were thirstier than Eva.
哦 你比伊娃渴
- Another one? - Oh, please.
- 要 - 好的 xx你
And then I won't bother you again.
然後就不再麻┠懔
Oh, no, no. It's no bother at all.
不 不的 完全不麻
Stay as long as you like.
你要待多久都可以
Ever since, uh... since Dad died, it's been pretty lonely out here.
自...我父H去世了 一人住在@Y很孤
You know, I'm just driving around
你知道 我就一直在附近巡
doing my rounds, with nothing but the radio and the occasional dispatch.
除了V播 偶被{派 ]e的事了
It's good to have someone to talk to when I come home.
回家r有人能跟我ff真好
伊娃很棒 但她竟不能跟我聊天
Eva's great and all，but not much for conversation.
- Here's your water. - You're not married?
- 你要的水 - 你]Y婚?
No, no. Have a seat. I was, you know, twice.
不 不是的 坐 我Y^婚...纱
The first one, uh, took my house,
第一老婆 ё吡宋业姆孔
the second one left before...
第二老婆 在袷鍪召
...the quarry takes this one.
@套房子之前x_了
That was...Ooh, hell, seven years already.
那是...哇 七年前的事了
I wouldn't mind getting another one,
我不介意再找一
but Bruneau ain't exactly the best singles scene
但布Z不是最m合紊淼娜说牡胤
and, well, I ain't exactly the best single.
而我 也不是S金紊h
Did your father ever talk to you about Germany?
你爸爸跟你起^德
Are you kidding me?
你在_玩笑
He never stopped talking about Germany.
他]停止^德
Did he ever speak to you about the war?
他有]有跟你f^P於二鸬氖?
Of course.
然
You know he was a collector, right?
你知道他是收集狂吧?
Ah.
啊
I got a bunch of his stuff. You wanna go take a look?
我有一堆他的|西 你想看看
Yeah.
好啊
Watch your step. Just come down here.
小心台A 就在@Y
Eva, quiet! Eva, shh.
伊娃 安o 伊娃 u
Hey, listen, uh, it's kind of a mess in here.
嘿 著 ~ @Y有cy
Let me just move some boxes and I'll...
我得把箱子挪_ 然後
I'll let you in the other room.
我你去另一房g
Here we go.
@
There we go. There. Come on. Oh!
倪@Y 好的 戆 哦
Come on in.
M戆
That was, uh...that was Dad's pride and joy.
那是 ~ 那是我爸爸的傲和快
The dealer he bought it from swore it was flying in Berlin on November 19, 1938.
那uo我的人l誓1938年11月19日@面旗迷诎亓诛w舞
Kristallnacht.
水晶之夜
Kristallnacht... Yeah.
Π 水晶之夜
Dad used to say that that flag, um,
父H曾f @面旗
witnessed the beginning of history.
C了v史的_端
You know?
你知道
- What is in these boxes?  - Uh, just...
- 箱子Y有什N? - ~ 就是
a bunch more of Dad's prize pieces. You know?
一些父H得到的其他p 你知道
I already sold most of the collection
我已u掉了大部分的收藏
but, uh, these are the things he was sentimental about.
但是 @些是跟他有感情的
Just haven't been able to let myself get rid of 'em, you know?
B我也]k法u了它 你知道
You wanna look around?
你想到看看
- Thank you. - Yeah.
- 感x - ]PS
Yeah, that was a first printing.
@是初刊本
A guy offered me six grand for it but I just... just couldn't part with it.
有人想用6000美元跟我I 但我就是]k法...u掉它
I guess I'm just as sentimental as my old man, huh?
我猜我跟我父H一痈星橛檬 Π
You're welcome to look around at... at anything you like.
你可以S便在周看看...任何|西都可以
I'm just gonna give Eva her dinner.
我去鸵镣渌的晚餐
Quiet! Shh!
安o u
Priceless, right?
or之 Π
Yeah.
Π
I guess I shouldn't leave it stuffed in a box like that.
我想我不把它像那尤在箱子Y面
You want another drink?
你想要再喝c什N
Yes. That would be good.
好的 那很好
More water,or something a little stronger?
再硪槐水 是烈一c的|西
Maybe something a little stronger.
烈一c的好了
All right.
好的
Now you're speaking my language.
F在你知道我在f什N了
Yeah...
是啊...
To Dad.
敬我父H
You know, my dad was, uh...
你知道 我爸他...
My dad was there that night.
我爸那天晚上在那
- What night was that? - Um, Kristal...
- 哪晚上 - ~ 水晶...
- Kristallnacht. - Yeah. Kristallnacht.
- 水晶之夜 -  水晶之夜
Yeah, he said he had a hammer
他f他Я艘FN
and he broke a bunch of jewelry store windows.
他打碎了一些珠店的窗
- He ever tell you that story? - No.
- 他跟你f^@件事 - ]有
No?
]有?
I so wish you were here when he was still alive.
我真希望你在他活著的r候磉@Y
You know, every once in a while, some of his buddies would come by
你知道 每^一段rg 有一些他的朋友^
and they'd just sit around, tell stories, drink, you know?
他就坐在@Y f一些故事 喝喝酒 你知道
He loved to talk about the old days.
他很喜gv一些以前的事
You okay? You're sweating there.
你好 你流了很多汗
- Oh, I feel a little hot. Yes. - Well, take your jacket off.
- 哦 我有c - 把你的外套了吧
Come here. Mmm.
戆
Yeah, take your jacket off and, hey, I just want to tell you something.
把你的外套了 然後 我只是想要告V你
- You are more than welcome... - Oh.
- 我求之不得你能... - 哦
...to spend the night if you like, if you don't mind sleeping in dad's old bed.
...在@Y住一晚 如果你不介意睡在我父H的f床上
- You're very kind. No, thank you.  - No, no.
- 你人真好 不必了 xx你 - 不 不
- Well, all right, the offer's on the table. - Oh, thank you.
- 好吧 反正我的提hSr有效 - 哦 xx你
Any friend of Dad's is a friend of mine.
父H的朋友就是我的朋友
How'd you know him? Did you serve with my dad?
你怎NJR他的 你曾跟他一起服役?
- No. - Well, how did you know him then?
- 不是 - 好吧 那你怎NJR他的
I knew him from Auschwitz.
我在W斯S辛JR他的
Auschwitz?
W斯S辛?
My dad wished he served at Auschwitz.
我父H很希望他能在W斯S辛服役
You mean your father was not at Auschwitz?
你是f你父H]去^W斯S辛?
What are you...
你在f什N...
Are you serious? My dad was a cook in the army.
你是J真的 我父H是的N
他不是集中II袖? He was not a Blockfuhrer?
I don't even know what that is. No, my dad was 10 when the war started.
我都不知道那是什N 不是 我父H在_始的r候才10q
Most that the Germans let him do was, you know,
德人他做的最多的事就是 你知道
break a bunch of windows and cook some Wiener Schnitzel, you know?
打破一些窗 煮一些S也{炸牛排 你知道
I am sorry to have bothered you.
很抱歉打_你了
- I have the wrong Rudy Kurlander. - No, no, no. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
- 我找e人了 - 不 ]事的 哇 哇塞
Wait a minute, you were at Auschwitz?
等一下 你以前在W斯S辛?
- Oh. - None of my dad's buddies served at a camp.
- 嗯 - ]有一我爸的朋友在那Y服役
I must leave you now. I have bothered you enough.
我必x_了 我已打_你很久了
Bothered me? No, no, no. Please stay.
打_我? 不 ]有 留下
Please stay. Share some stories.
留下 分享一些故事吧
I'll grab another bottle. We'll just...
我再去拿一瓶酒 我就...
What's that?
那是什N
What is that?
What the fuck is that?
那他的是什N
Well... I'm sorry. I...
~...Σ黄 我...
I, uh...
我 ~...
What the fuck is that?
那他的是什N
Are you a Jew?
你是q太人?
Yeah.
是的
You're a Jew?
你是一q太人?
What the fuck's going on here?
F在他是怎N回事
I'm sorry, I...
Σ黄 我...
Sit the fuck down.
干你娘 o我坐下
Please, let me go.
拜你 我走吧
What the fuck are you doing in my house?
你他在我家
I made a mistake. Your father is the wrong man.
我搞e了 你父H不是我要找的人
My father?
我父H?
You said you were a friend of my dad.
你f你是我父H的朋友
You lied to me.
你_我
- I did not lie. I did not lie! - Jesus fucking Christ.
- 我]有fe 我]有fe - 干你娘u掰
You said you were a friend of my dad, you come into my house
你f你是我父H的朋友 你到我家Y
and you drink my fucking whiskey,
他的喝我的威士忌
and you're a dirty fucking Jew.
而你他是一av的q太人
Eva, shut the fuck up!
伊娃 ]上你的狗嘴
Stop yelling! Please, stop yelling! I will go.
e吼了 求你了 e再吼了 我走
Sit the fuck down!
你o我坐下
You gotta answer some questions right fucking now!
你他F在立刻回答我的}
Holy shit! Did you just piss on my couch?
操你的 你是尿在了我的沙l上
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. - What the fuck?
- Σ黄 我很抱歉 - 操你
Stop yelling!
e再叫了
Eva, shut the fuck up!
伊娃 你他]嘴
Are you giving me a fucking order, Jew?
你是在命令我 q太人
Eva, I said, "Shut the fuck up!" You know...
伊娃 我你]嘴 你知道...
you know what my dad would say if he knew a fucking Jew was in his house, huh?
你知道如果我父H知道他有一q太人在他家他f什N
He would say, "Heil fucking Hitler."
他f "希特勒他的fq"
That's what he'd say. Yeah.
]e 那就是他f的
Heil fucking Hitler! Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
希特勒他的fq! 希特勒fq! 希特勒fq!
Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler, you fucking Jew!
希特勒fq! 希特勒fq 你他的q太人!
Eva, goddamn it, shut the fuck up!
伊娃 死的 o我安o
Shut up! What's your problem?
]嘴 你有什N}啊
Huh? Shut up!
哈? ]嘴
Stop it! Eva, quiet!
停下 伊娃 安o
Eva!
伊娃
Damn it, shut up! Shut up, damn it! Quiet!
死 ]嘴 ]嘴 操你 安o
Eva, settle down.
伊娃 冷o下
You want to meet a real life fucking Jew?
你他想要去活生生的q太人
Huh? Huh?
哈 是
Huh? Go get him.
哈 去抓他吧
Ah!
啊!
What the...
我操你...
You fucking kike!
你@死的q太人
You fucking...
我操...
Oh...
哦...
You've reached John Kurlander.
@是s翰・焯m德
Leave me a message. Or if it's an emergency, call my cell phone.
留言吧 如果有急事 打我的手C
Ruth?
露z?
Where you at, John? You're a half hour late
s翰 你在哪 你已晚了半小r了
and I can't cover your ass all morning.
我不能整早上都湍阊谧o
- I swear, you best be having car trouble... - What are you saying?
- 我l誓 你最好是出了... - 你在f什N
My God.
我的天啊
Oh...
哦...
Hello.
你好
- Max, it's Zev. - Where have you been?
- R克思 我是煞 - 你去哪了
I killed a man.
我⒘艘人
Uh...
~...
Now is the hardest part. You must call the police.
F在是最y的部分了 你必缶
- You must... - No, no!
- 你必... - 不 不是的
He was not the man we are looking for.
他不是我要找的人
- Who was he? - It was a much younger man.
- 那是l - 一年p很多的男人
I, uh... I saw his name on a box.
我 ~... 在一箱子上看到了他的名字
It was John Kurlander.
他叫做s翰・焯m德
He is a Nazi.
他是一{粹
- How do you know this? - There were many Nazi things
- 你怎N知道的 - 有很多{粹的|西
- in the house. Many things. - Oh.
- 在房gY 有很多|西 - 哦
This is not what we set out to do.
@不是我的初衷
Zev.
煞
Do you want to continue?
你想^m
Yes, I must finish.
我想 我必完成
I must.
我必
After all, this is the man who killed our families.
竟 那是⒘宋全家的人
Ruth?
露z?
Ruth!
露z!
Hello.
喂
Yes.
我是
Oh, my God. Thank you. Thank you so much.
哦 我的天啊 xx你 太感x你了
Is he okay?
他好
No, he has dementia. Mm-hmm.
不 他有V呆
I'm sorry. Uh...
不好意思 ~
Where are you calling from? I can be there right away.
你是哪难Y打淼? 我R上^去
Reno Memorial Hospital?
YZo念t院?
- Reno, Nevada? - Reno?
- YZ 热A_州? - YZ?
Is it possible that I could speak with my father?
我可以跟我父Hv
Yeah, thank you. Thank you very much.
好的 xx 非常感x你
Guys, I gotta sneeze.
夥 我要打嚏了
Hello.
喂
Oh, hello, Charles.
哦 你好啊 查斯
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm fine. I'm fine.
是啊 哦 我很好 e心
Thank you.
xx你
I told the doctors not to bother you.
我叫t生e去打_你
Huh?
哈
Please, don't you worry about me.
你e心我了
No. No. No. Don't you come to the hospital.
哦 不 不用的 你e磲t院
Your mother will pick me up.
你母H斫游业
Maybe you come with her, huh?
你跟她一起?
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Goodbye. Goodbye.
Π 我很好 ]事的 嗯 好的 再
Do you like cartoons?
你喜g卡通?
I like Disney Channel.
我喜g迪士尼l道的
- Mickey Mouse? - No. I like Phineas and Ferb.
- 米老鼠 - 不是 我喜gw哥c小佛
Oh.
哦
I never heard of them.
我]f^他
I'll be right back, Molly.
莫利 我R上回
You finish your homework please.
你快做你的功n吧
- Your name is Molly? - Molly Elizabeth.
- 你叫莫利? - 莫利・伊莎白
Do you like sweets, Molly Elizabeth?
你喜g糖果 莫利・伊莎白
Well, uh...
好的 ~
I think there are some caramels in my coat pocket.
我想我的大衣口袋Y有一些硬糖
I always keep some there for my grandchildren.
我一直槲业O子湟恍┰谀茄Y
Ah.
啊
I can't find any.
我找不到
Well, my wife will bring some when she comes.
好吧 我妻子淼r候б恍┑
- Are you Zev? - Yes.
- 你是煞 - 是的
Can I open your letter?
我能看你的信
Uh-huh.
可以啊
- Whoa, you're rich! - What?
- 哇 你真有X - 什N?
Who's Max?
l是R克思
Max?
R克思?
I'm not sure.
我不清楚
Wait. Why don't you read the letter to me out loud?
等等 要不然你把信xo我吧
"Zev, there are some difficult things you must know."
"煞 有些事令人y以接受 可你得知道"
"Firstly, Ruth has passed away."
"首先 露z已^世了"
"She had cancer."
"她得了癌Y"
"She loved you and you were with her, holding her hand, at the end."
"她勰 在她最後的r刻 你陪在她身 握著她的手"
"Secondly, you have dementia."
"其次 你患有V呆Y"
"Recently you have been forgetting many things."
"最近你得健忘了"
That's normal. Old people always forget things.
那很正常 老年人是弁事
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊 是啊
"You and I have a similar history."
"我有著相似的v"
"We are both Auschwitz..."
"我都是W斯S辛..."
Auschwitz. Auschwitz.        "Auschwitz survivors."
- W斯S辛 W斯S辛 - "W斯S辛的存者"
"Look at your left arm, you were prisoner 98814."
"看看你的左臂 你是98814囚犯"
"When the war ended,"
"Y束r"
"I promised myself"
"我承Z自己"
"I would find the men responsible."
"我要找到那些榇素的人"
"Working with Simon Wiesenthal,"
"c西蒙・威森塔共事期g"
"I have helped to capture dozens of former Nazis"
"我兔ψカ@了大批前'{'分子"
"all around the world."
"他遍咽澜绺鞯"
What's a Nazi?        Nazi. Nazi.
- '{'是什N       - 是{粹 {粹
A bad person.
一N娜
Six months ago, God smiled upon me
六月前 上帝n我好\
when you moved to the senior housing community.
你搬到高社^後
I immediately recognized you from Auschwitz,
我立刻就J出了那曾在W斯S辛的你
although you did not remember me.
管你已不得我
We are the last living survivors from our prison block.
我是那z^健在的最後的存者
Besides me, you are the only person
除我之外 你是唯一一
who could still recognize the face of the man who murdered our families.
能J出⒑ξ家人的词置婵椎娜
Simon Wiesenthal insisted
西蒙・威森塔猿终J
that all war criminals be given public trials.
所有鸱付受到公_判
However, we cannot give Wallisch that opportunity.
但是 我不能o瓦利施@C
Even if there was enough proof,
管C_
he, like us, would probably die
他 跟我一 很可能
before he could be extradited to Germany.
在被引渡德之前已去世
We have agreed that Otto Wallisch must die.
我都同 W托・瓦利施必死
You must kill him.
你必⒘怂
"You promised to go once Ruth died.
"你答等露z去世你就去"
"You promised me and you promised Ruth."
"你答了我 你也答了露z"
You did a very good job.
你x得很棒
Thanks.
xx
Who's Ruth?
露z是l
My wife.
我的妻子
I thought she was bringing me candy.
我以樗能c糖果o我
I thought so, too.
我也希望碇
Yes, I need to go to Holiday Inn Express
我要去假日旅^
3961 Lake Tahoe Boulevard.
塔霍湖大道3961
South Lake?         Yeah.
- 在湖南岸 -
That's over an hour away.
那得一多小r
Oh, that's... I have money.        Hop in.
- 哦 那... 我蝈X了 - 上吧
Hello. Zev?        Yeah.
- 你好 煞? - 是的
Thank God.
感x上帝
Where are you?
你在哪
Zev?
煞?
Tahoe.
塔霍
You understand what you must do
你明白你怎N做
There's only one left.
只剩一人了
Yeah, I understand...
是的 我明白
what I must do.
我怎N做
Morning.        Good morning.
- 早 - 早上好
I'd like to check out, please.
我想退房
Thank you.
xx你
You hurt your hand?        Oh, yes, yes.
- 你的手受了? - 哦  是的
It's... Well, I can move.        Good.
- 它...好了 能 - 不e
Okay, that'll be $106.20.
好的 共106美元20美分
I think I will have enough money for the taxi.
我想搭出租的X是蛄
Oh, uh, we take credit cards, too.
哦 呃 我也能用信用卡的
Yeah.
是啊
Thank you.
xx你
Tahoe? What the heck is he doing in Tahoe?
塔霍? 他在塔霍搞什N鬼
No, I'm just picking up a rental now
不 我正在租
and I guess I'll just drive up there.
我想我_^去
Yeah.
好
Oh, look, can you try and find
哦 著 你能著找到
the name of the taxi company that picked him up?
他搭的那v出租所俟司的名字
Thank you.
xx你
Can I help you?
需要兔
Rudy Kurlander, he lives here?
迪・焯m德 他在@住
Yes.        Can I speak with him?
- 是的 - 我能跟他聊聊
He's still sleeping.         Oh.
- 他在睡X - 哦
Well, could I wait for him to... wake up?
好吧 我能在@等他...醒
It's important.
是要o事
What's this about?
什N事啊
Well, it's private.
呃 是私事
And he knows me, he knows me.
而且他J得我 他J得我
I knew him a long time ago.
我很久以前就JR他了
Come on in.        Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- M戆 - 哦 xx你 xx你
Do you want a cup of coffee, Mr...        Guttman.
- 需要肀咖啡 您叫... - 古特曼
Yes, coffee would be nice. Thank you.
行 咖啡挺好 xx你
Uh, just black.        Take a seat in the living room.
- 呃 黑咖啡就好 - 在客d坐
I've got a pot brewing.
我去煮咖啡
That's from our family reunion a couple years ago.
那是我家啄昵爸鼐鄣r候照的
Oh.
噢
You have a big family.
真是大家庭
My father likes to say he fielded a soccer team.
我父H壅f他生了一支足球
I'm his youngest.
我是老小
How old was your mother?
你母H有多大
She was a lot younger. It was his second marriage.
她年p多了 父H是二婚
Thank you.        Can I ask you a question, Mr. Guttman?
- xx你 - 古特曼先生 我能您}N
Does you being here have to do with Auschwitz?
您的事跟W斯S辛有PN
Yes.
是的
My father's not gonna want to talk about that.
我父H可不那事
Oh.
哦
I understand.
我理解
Would you like to join us for breakfast, Mr. Guttman?
您意跟我共M早餐 古特曼先生
I'm making baked apple pancakes.
我做了些烤O果
I'm not very hungry. Thank you very much.
我不太I 真是感x你
I won't bother you for long.
我不打_你太久的
Are you sure? It's an old family recipe.
你_定? @可是家髅匮u
Mmm. Yes, I am sure, but thank you just the same.
嗯 是的 我_定 可是xx你
If you'd excuse me, I am just going to run up and tell Dad you're here.
您等我下 我去告V父H您砹
Yeah, yeah.
好 好的
Uh, who are you?
呃 你是l
Oh, I am Zev.
哦 我是煞
Hi, Zev.       Inge
- 嗨 煞 - 英格
Who is that?
那是l
Well, it's an old friend of your grandfather.
那是你外公的老朋友
You like Wagner?
你喜g瓦格{?
Yes. I have always loved Wagner.
是啊 我一直都喜弁吒窦{
My daughter said someone I knew from Auschwitz was here.
我女赫f砹我JR的W斯S辛人
But a survivor should not like Wagner, no?
但作橐存者不喜g瓦格{的 不是 (瓦格{ 德作曲家 N族主x者 反q太主x者)
You can't hate music.
音酚植豢珊
I, uh, didn't recognize your face in those pictures.
我 呃 ]能在那些照片中J出你
But...
但是...
Your voice...
你的音...
has not changed.
]
I knew you would come to find me one day.
我知道有一天你碚椅
Zev's your friend, Poppy?
外公 煞蚴悄闩笥
Inge, please go back into the kitchen.
英格 你回N房去
My friend and I need to discuss some things.
我得跟我朋友探些事
I have not forgotten you.
我]忘你
Please... let us go outside.
戆...我到外面去
I do not want my family to hear...what we have to say.
我不想我的家人...我要f的事
It has been a long time...
已有很久...
since anyone knew who I was.
]人J出那暗奈伊
I cannot even remember when.
我甚至不清有多久
Over the years people have looked at me
@些年 人盯著我看
and I think they know, but they never do.
我就以樗J出我了 其他]有
Or maybe they were just too scared to say anything.
或S他只是太害怕 所以什N都不敢f
Sometimes, I come out here and speak my name.
有r候 我到@ f出自己的名字
I talk to myself.
我自言自Z
I remind myself of who I was.
重新回起以前的那我
It is the only way to know I existed...
@是唯一一N我知道自己存在^的方式
before I became who I am now.
在我成F在@人之前的那自我
Well, living a lie is not a life.
好吧 靠e言^活算什N人生
I always knew you would find me.
我一直都知道你找到我
It has been too long.
已^了太久
We are old men now.
F在我都是老人了
Take your hands off of me, Otto.
把你的手拿_ W托
Excuse me?
什N
I said, "Take your hands off of me."
我f "把你的手拿_"
You called me Otto.
你叫我W托?
I think you're confused.
我想你弄糊T了
No, your name is Otto Wallisch.
]有 你的名字叫W托・瓦利施
你是W斯S辛的一zL You were a Blockfuhrer at Auschwitz.
And you killed my family.
你⒘宋业募胰
Are you crazy?
你了
You've lived a lie for so long
你自欺欺人@N久
you've convinced yourself it is true.
你自己都信以檎媪
I...
我...
I do not understand.
我不明白
Let me help you...
那我湍
understand.
弄明白
It's like we're running a hotel.
感X像我_了家旅^
Go tell Pop-Pop breakfast is ready.
去告V外公早好了
Who is it?        My name's Charles Guttman.
- 是l啊 - 我叫查斯・古特曼
I think my father's here.
我想我父H在@
Hi, I'm so sorry to bother you,
嗨 真抱歉打_您
but I was told that a taxi dropped my dad off here a little while ago.
可是我f不久前有v出租d我爸爸到@
Yeah, he's outside with my father.
是啊 他跟我父H在外面
Thank God.
感x上帝
He's been missing for a week.
他已失一周了
Missing?
失?
I had no idea. Come on.        Thank you.
- y以置信 跟我 - xx
Dad?        Oh, my God.
- 爸? - 哦 上帝啊
Mommy?        Please do not be frightened.
-  - eo
Don't be scared.
e害怕
Dad, why don't you, uh, lower the gun?
爸 你槭颤N不 呃 把放低些
Charles?        Yeah.
- 查斯? - 啊
What are you doing here?       Uh...
- 你在@致 - 呃...
Dad, put the gun down.
爸 把放下
Put down the gun, Dad.        No. No.
- 把放下 爸 - 不 不
Not until he tells the truth.
除非他f出真相
Why are you doing this?
槭颤N你要@幼
Tell them who you are.
告V她你是l
Please, stop this madness.
你el了
Tell them what you did.
告V她你做了什N
Leave them alone, please.        English!
- 放^她 拜了 - f英Z
I beg you.
我求你了
I want them to understand what you're saying.
我要她懂你f的
Dad, what is he talking about?
爸爸 他在f什N啊
Do not listen to him. He is crazy!
e他的 他了
Ach so?
是
You have a very easy choice.
你的x窈芎
You can tell the truth and she lives,
你可以f出真相她活下
or you can lie and watch her die.
你也可以撒e 然後看著她倒下
You have three seconds.
o你三秒
One.        Please stop.
- 一 - 拜 e@
Two.        Please, just shoot me.
- 二 - 求你了 朝我_吧
Dad, stop it!        Three.
- 爸 停下 - 三
Okay. Okay.
好吧 好吧
Okay.
好吧
During the war,
在期g
I was not a prisoner.
我不是囚犯
Louder.
大c
During the war I was not a prisoner.        Louder!
- 在期g我不是囚犯 - 再大c!
During the war I was not a prisoner!
在期g我不是囚犯!
I was a Nazi.
我是{粹
I was SS.
我是hl
我是W斯S辛集中I的一zL I was a Blockfuhrer at Auschwitz.
Did you kill people?
你⑦^人
Yes.
是的
You killed people, Poppy?        How many people did you kill?
-  你⑦^人? - 你⒘硕嗌偃
I don't know.
我不清楚
Many.
很多人
And now tell them your real name.
F在告V她你的真名
My name is...
我的名字叫...
Kunibert Sturm.
炷岵特・斯德姆
No.
不
Your name is Wallisch!
你的名字叫瓦利施!
No, it's Kunibert Sturm.
不 就是炷岵特・斯德姆
You are Otto Wallisch!
你叫W托・瓦利施!
No.
不
You! You are Otto Wallisch!
是你 你叫W托・瓦利施
You're lying.
你在撒e
No.
]有
It's the first time I haven't lied in 70 years.
@是70年砦业谝淮握f真
You are Otto Wallisch.
你才是W托・瓦利施
I am Kunibert Sturm. We were both Blockfuhrers.
我是炷岵特・斯德姆 我都是W斯S辛的zL
No...
不...
I was a prisoner.
我是囚犯
Look at your arm.
看看你的胳膊
You are number 98814. I am 98813.
你是98814 我是98813
We tattooed each other. It was our only way to escape.
是我互相y的 @是我唯一的逃生k法
Dad?
爸?
Is that true?
是真的
No, it's all lies. It's all lies.
不 都是e言 都是e言
It's not true.
@不是真的
Lies?
e言?
How could you forget?
你怎N能忘呢
You took the name Zev because it means wolf.
你o自己取名叫煞 因樗是狼的意思
You said we were wolves!
你f我z都是狼
Oh, my God.
哦 我的上帝
I remember.
我得
Dad?
爸?
Dad!
爸
Right now, we're still waiting
F在 我在等待
to hear from the Lake Tahoe Police Department.
碜运霍湖警察局的消息
They haven't spoken to reporters or released a statement just yet.
他仍未向者透露或l压俜铰明
But they have assured us
但他向我保C
that we will hear from them in some way within the hour.
不出一小r我⑾但@知
Residents, though, are,as you can imagine, just stunned.
居民 如你所想的那 十分震@
I've spoken to some people who do not want to comment on camera.
我同一些不在z像C前l表言的人了
I did speak to one, though, who told me that...
其中一位告V我...
Poor Zev.        Tragic. Absolutely tragic.
- 可z的煞 - 悲 真正的悲
He couldn't have known what he was doing.
他一定不知道他在做什N
He knew exactly what he was doing.
他很清楚他在做什N
What? What are you talking about, Max?
什N 你是什N意思 R克斯
The man he killed
他⒌舻哪人
was named Kunibert Sturm.
叫做炷岵特・斯德姆
And Zev's name
而煞虻恼婷
was Otto Wallisch.
叫做W托・瓦利施
They were the men who...
就是他...
murdered my family.
⒑α宋业募胰